A Guide to the Papers of William White, 1875-1987
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Manuscripts
  - William White
    - 'Whitman's "To a Locomotive in Winter": A Study of the Worksheets' 1960 (Box 5)
    - "The Textual Evolution of the Poetry of A.E. Housman" William White's dissertation 1953 Jun 3, TMs (Box 5)
  - Others
    - "The Aesthetics of the Hemingway Hero" by K.K. Shukla ca. 1978, TMs, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - "Bibliography of Walt Whitman" by Charles N. Eliot 1947 Apr 21, TMs (carbon) (Box 6)
    - "Ernest M. Hemingway, Newspaperman: The Toronto Star Stories, 1920-1924" by Randall Scott Davis 1983, TMs, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Hemingway's Paris by Robert E. Gajdusek, with a review 1978 Nov, Electostatic copy (Box 6)
    - A.E. Housman Poetry, and letters of Grant Richards, M.I. Jackson, and Geoffrey [Wethered] 1875-1934, 6 TMs (Box 7)
    - Nathanael West: An Interpretative Study by James F. Light n.d., Galleys (Box 7)
    - "Walt Whitman Bibliography" by Verne Dyson ca. 1960, TMs (Box 7)
    - Manuscripts submitted to the Walt Whitman Quarterly Review1985-1986, n.d., TMs, 3 folders (Box 7)
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence: A 1937-1972, & 1978-1985 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: B 1952-1973, & 1981-1985 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence w/ Carlos Baker 1961-1969 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence w/ Book Dealers 1946-1987 (Box 8)
  - Letters from Ernest Bramah 1900-1940, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence re Ernest Bramah 1957-1986, n.d., 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Correspondence w/ Matthew Bruccoli 1968-1969, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: C 1938-1979, & 1985 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence re Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature 1954-1969 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence re Censorship 1954-1958 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence w/ Charles Scribner's Sons 1962, 1965-1986, n.d., 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Correspondence re G.K. Chesterton 1982-1984 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: D 1950-1967, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence re Emily Dickinson 1946-1986 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence re John Donne 1937-1938, 1946-1969 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: E 1938-1957 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence re Ralph Waldo Emerson 1938, 1961-1963 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence re Employment 1937-1985 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: F 1937-1979 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: G 1938-1977, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: H 1937-1974, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence of E.R. Hagemann and William White re Hemingway 1968-1969, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence w/ Audre Hanneman 1965-1967, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence re Ernest Hemingway 1946-1987, n.d., 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Correspondence of William Nolan and William White re Hemingway 1967-1979, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence re Hemingway Notes 1971-1987 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence re A.E. Housman 1936-1987, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Correspondence of Houston Martin and William White re A.E. Housman 1939-1957 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence re the International Imitation Hemingway Competition 1978-1986 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence w/ Joseph Ishill 1957-1966 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: J, K, L 1937-1972, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence re D.H. Lawrence 1949-1962 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: M 1938-1967, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: O 1960-1970, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence w/ the Oita College of Commerce (Japan) 1939-1941 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence re Sir William Osler 1937-1969 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: P, R 1938-1963, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: S, T 1937-1966, 1977, 1985, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence w/ Karl Shapiro 1958-1963, 1978-1981 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence w/ W.D. Snodgrass 1972-1979, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence re W.D. Snodgrass 1960-1961, 1975-1980 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence re Henry David Thoreau 1937-1949 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence w/ the University of Madras (India) 1984-1986 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: V-Z 1948-1973, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence re Nathanael West 1953-1980, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence re Walt Whitman 1956-1987, 6 folders (Box 13)
  - Correspondence of Emory Holloway re Walt Whitman 1917-1943, 1953-1970 (Box 13)
- Research Material
  - Ernest Bramah Articles by William White 1959-1984, n.d., 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Ernest Bramah Correspondence n.d., Copies (Box 14)
  - Ernest Bramah Manuscripts n.d., Copies (Box 14)
  - Ernest Bramah Manuscripts n.d., Copies (Box 15)
  - Ernest Bramah Miscellaneous Notes n.d. (Box 15)
  - Emily Dickinson Articles by William White 1969, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Emily Dickinson Miscellaneous Notes n.d. (Box 15)
  - Ernest Hemingway Articles by William White 1949, 1961-1986, n.d., 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Ernest Hemingway Bibliography and Checklist 1970-1981, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Ernest Hemingway Miscellaneous Notes 1967, 1985, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Ernest Hemingway North American Newspaper Alliance Dispatches n.d. (Box 16)
  - A.E. Housman Articles by William White 1942-1970, n.d. (Box 16)
  - A.E. Housman A Bibliography [ca. 1982] (Box 16)
  - Checklist of A.E. Housman's Writings in Latin 1968 (Box 16)
  - A.E. Housman Correspondence n.d., Copies (Box 16)
  - A.E. Housman Manuscripts n.d., Copies (Box 16)
  - A.E. Housman Miscellaneous Notes n.d. (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Articles by William White 1941-1987, n.d., 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Bibliographies 1939-1969 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Notes n.d. (Box 17)
  - William Osler Articles by William White 1937-1965 (Box 17)
  - Theodore Roethke Correspondence 1986, Copies (Box 17)
  - Karl Shapiro Miscellaneous Notes 1960-1962, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Percy Shelley Miscellaneous Notes 1939-1954 (Box 18)
  - Dylan Thomas Miscellaneous Notes 1951-1957, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Henry David Thoreau Miscellaneous Notes 1938-1956, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Nathanael West Articles by William White 1957-1972, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Nathanael West Miscellaneous Notes 1968, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Walt Whitman Articles by William White 1939, 1958-1975, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Contemporary Reviews of Walt Whitman's Leaves of Grassn.d. (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman Correspondence & Manuscripts Copies n.d., 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman in The Criticn.d. (Box 19)
  - Descriptive Bibliography of Walt Whitman n.d. (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman - Horace Traubel's Notes for With Walt Whitman in Camden, 1890 Jul-1891 Jun [1986-1987], 5 folders (Box 20)
  - Walt Whitman - Horace Traubel's Notes for With Walt Whitman in Camden, 1891 Sep-1892 Mar [1986-1987], 6 folders (Box 21)
  - Walt Whitman Miscellaneous Notes n.d., 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Walt Whitman in the New Orleans Daily Crescentn.d. (Box 22)
  - Walt Whitman: As Man, Poet, and Friend collected by Charles A. Eliot n.d., Copies (Box 22)
- Printed Material
  - Ernest Bramah Printed Material 1883-1986, n.d., 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Emily Dickinson Printed Material 1938-1987, n.d., 3 folders (Box 23)
  - "Essays in Americana" by William White Newsclippings 1937-1938 (Box 23)
  - Ernest Hemingway Newsclippings 1926, 1935-1959, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Ernest Hemingway Newsclippings 1960-1987, n.d., 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Ernest Hemingway Printed Material 1927-1979, 5 folders (Box 25)
  - Ernest Hemingway Printed Material 1980-1987, n.d., 3 folders (Box 26)
  - A.E. Housman Printed Material 1897, 1922-1986, n.d., 3 folders (Box 26)
  - International Imitation Hemingway Competition Printed Material 1979-1986 (Box 26)
  - D.H. Lawrence Printed Material 1948-1960, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous Newsclippings 1951-1984, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material 1941-1969, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous Authors Printed Material 1948-1985, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Obscenity: Printed Material re 1955-1968, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Sir William Osler Printed Material 1931-1970, n.d. (Box 27)
  - S.J. Perelman Printed Material 1922, 1964, & 1970 (Box 27)
  - Nathanael West Printed Material 1929-1986, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Walt Whitman Printed Material 1891-1936, 1952-1986, n.d., 4 folders (Box 28)
  - Walt Whitman The Long Islander Supplements 1959-1985 (Box 28)
  - Walt Whitman Newsclippings 1891-1987, n.d. (Box 28)
  - William White Newsclippings 1930-1986, n.d. (Box 29)
- Miscellaneous Papers
  - Censorship 1954-1967, n.d., 2 folders (Box 29)
  - International Imitation Hemingway Competition n.d., 2 folders (Box 29)
  - International Imitation Hemingway Competition n.d. (Box 30)
  - Personal Papers - Army 1941-1947 (Box 30)
  - Personal Papers - Bibliography of William White n.d. (Box 30)
  - Personal Papers - Biographical 1950-1985 (Box 30)
  - Personal Papers - Miscellaneous 1937-1957 (Box 30)
  - Photographs of Ernest Bramah n.d. (Box 30)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous 1948, n.d. (Box 30)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous Authors ca. 1936-1974 (Box 30)
  - Photographs of the White Family ca. 1958-1970, n.d. (Box 30)
  - Photographs of Walt Whitman n.d. (Box 30)
  - Syllabi and Examinations for Journalism and Literature Classes n.d. (Box 30)
- Diaries of William White
  - Diaries 1928, 1931-1943 Jul, 14 volumes (Box 31)
  - Diaries 1943 Jul-1948 Oct, 1951-1953, 1976, 1978, & 1980, 12 volumes (Box 32)
- Microfilm/ Cassette Recordings/ Phonograph Records
  - A.E. Housman Correspondence from the University of London Library 1900-1935, Microfilm
  - A.E. Housman Correspondence from the British Library, Manuscript
    Additional Manuscript #44923-4
  - A.E. Housman Miscellaneous Correspondence, Unidentified Source, Microfilm
  - "John O'Hara: Remarks on the Novel" The Library of Congress Whittal Lecture January 14, 1957, Cassette Recordings
  - "The Day of the Locust" (Nathanael West) lecture by Kingsley Widmer for the series: 20th 1975, Cassette Recording
  - "A Farewell to Arms" by Ernest Hemingway, an NBC Star Playhouse starring Frederick n.d., Cassette Recording
  - Readings by Ernest Hemingway: Nobel Prize Speech, "Second Poem to Mary," "In Harry's 1965, Phonograph Recording
  - "Hemingway - A Portrait in Sound" interviews re Hemingway's life and work May 26, 1970, Phonograph Recording
  - Poems and letters of Emily Dickinson, read by Julie Harris n.d., Phonograph Recording
  - "Emily Dickinson: A Self Portrait" poems and letters read by Julie Harris 1968, Phonograph Recording
- Personal Keepsakes and Mementoes 1912-1938, Scrapbook
- School Newspapers 1926-1932, Scrapbook
- Photostats of the New York Sunday DispatchOctober 14, 1849-May 19, 1850 (Oversize S-9: Folder 1)
- Engravings of "The Virgin and the Dragonfly" signed by Charles Feinberg as a Christmas (Oversize S-9: Folder 1)
- Broadside re Hemingway Conference in San Diego, California, March 27 & 28 (Oversize S-9: Folder 1)
- 24 Printed Articles re Ernest Hemingway (Oversize S-9: Folder 2)
- Print of Sir William Osler (Oversize S-9: Folder 3)
- Eight Selections of Sheet Music with lyrics from A.E. Housman's poetry 1904-1948 (Oversize S-9: Folder 3)